Guide to the Records of the American Institute of the City of New York for the Encouragement of Science and Invention 1808-1983 (Bulk 1828-1940) MS 17
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Pamphlets & Publications, 1829-1941, undated
  - Subseries 1: American Institute Pamphlets & Publications, 1829-1941
    This subseries contains publications of the American Institute. These include the nineteenth century Journal of the American Institute (Vol. I-IV, 1835-1839); Annual Fair publications (i.e., premium lists); printed addresses on topics such as agriculture, gardening, sanitation; and annual reports and proceedings. In addition, material from the 1890s concerns photography and the American Institute's photographic salon. Bound Transactions of the American Institute cover the years 1847 to 1872.
    Twentieth century material includes annual reports, items related to the annual fairs, and material from 1930s Children's Fairs and Salons of Photography. American Institute publications for children and young adults include Science Leaflet (Jan. 4, 1934; Sept. 14, 1939-May 8, 1941), Amateur Scientist (May 1937-March 1938), Science Observer (Dec. 1938-July 1941), and March of Science (Sept. 17, 1932-Feb. 23, 1937).
    Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 466-468 and bound volumes.
  - Subseries 2: Non-American Institute Pamphlets & Publications, 1933, undated
    This subseries contains publications not produced by the American Institute, including books and publications from the institute's private library.
    Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 469-479.
- Series V: Visual Materials, 1926-1927, undated
  This series contains mostly photographs and prints, the bulk of which are oversize or were removed from frames. These include photos of American Institute fairs and exhibits, experiments and equipment; portraits of scientists, museum curators, and science industry personnel; photos of American Institute buildings; a group portrait of the Junior Radio Club; photos of a diagram of the 1939 World's Fair; and photos of airships and mines. The bulk of photographs are undated, probably circa 1920s-1930s. Prints are generally mounted nineteenth century newspaper sketches. Also included are photostats and carbon stencils.
  This series also contains framed portraits of American Institute presidents:
  A. Cressy Morrison, 1930-1932
  H. Horton Sheldon, 1932-1934
  Alfred Knight, 1934-1936
  Robert T. Pollock, 1936-1940
  Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 480-483.
- Series VI: Artifacts, undated
  This series contains various American Institute artifacts. Included are pins, ribbons, medals, and medal cases; a nineteenth century ballot/ticket, voting and cash boxes; printing blocks and wax seals; exhibit labels; and a letter opener.
  Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 484-491.